export const questions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "How many times can you perform leading zero compression in a single IPV6 address?",
    options: [
      "As often as you like",
      "Only once",
      "Twice",
      "You cannot perform this type of compression in an IPV6 address",
    ],
    answer: "As often as you like",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question:
      "Which layer of the OSI model is responsible for specifying the encapsulation method used for specific types of media?",
    options: ["Application", "Transport", "Physical", "Datalink"],
    answer: "Application",
  },
  {
    id: 3,

    question:
      "Which layer of the OSI model is included in the Internet layer of the TCP/IP model ?",
    options: ["Network", "Application", "Transport", "Datalink"],
    answer: "1",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "What are the two services performed by the data link layer of the OSI model?",
    options: [
      "It encrypts data packets",
      "It determtnes the path to forward packets",
      "It accepts Layer 3 packets and encapsulates them into frames",
      "It provides media access control and performs error detection",
    ],
    answer: "Using Array.map() method",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question:
      "What two application layer protocols are part of TCP/IP protcol suite? ( Chooese two)",
    options: ["ARP", "FTP", "DNS", "NAT"],
    answer: "Internal storage of component",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "In which CLI configuration mode can you configure the hostname of a device?",
    options: ["Line", "Interface", "GlcDal", "Router"],
    answer: "npx install create-react-app my-app",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question:
      "Which type of topology requires less cabling as compared to Mesh and still provides good protection(data can flow from other side, if on elink is broken)?",
    options: [
      "Ring Network Topology",
      "Bus Network Topology",
      "Star Network Topology",
      "Point to Point Network Topology",
    ],
    answer: "props",
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "At which layer of the OSI model would a logical address be encapsulated?",
    options: [
      "Physical Layer",
      "Network Layer",
      "Data link Layer",
      "Transport Layer",
    ],
    answer: "Flux",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "Which of the following layers of the OSI model is responsible for user interaction?",
    options: ["Layer 4", "Layer 5", "Layer 6", "Layer 7"],
    answer: "It is a module bundler",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      "which PDU is processed when a host computer is de-encapsulating a message at the transport layer of the TCP/IP model?",
    options: ["Bits", "Frame", "Packet", "Segment"],
    answer: "All of these",
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question:
      "What method can be used by two computers to ensure that packets are not dropped because too much data is being sent too quickly?",
    options: [
      "Encapsulation",
      "Flow control",
      "Access method",
      "Response timeout",
    ],
    answer: "Invoking the code after the setState operation is performed",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question:
      "Which type of Network Topology is most common to avoid Layer-2 network loops?",
    options: [
      "Ring Network Topology",
      "Tree Network Topology",
      "Starhqetwork Topology",
      "Bus Network Topology",
    ],
    answer: "Unique among the siblings only",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question:
      "You suspect a router interface is malfunctioning. In which mode can you verify its status?",
    options: [
      "Privileged Mode",
      "Global Configuration Mode",
      "User Mode",
      "ROM Monitor Mode",
    ],
    answer: "ReactDOM.render()",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question:
      "WAN technologies, such as X.25 and ATM, would use what layer of the OSI model?",
    options: [
      "Application layer",
      "Transport layer",
      "Network Layer",
      "Datalink",
    ],
    answer: "User interface",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question:
      "what process is used to place one message inside another message for transfer from the source to the destination?",
    options: ["Access Control", "Decoding", "Encapsulation", "Flow Control"],
    answer: "renderComponent",
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question:
      "Which PDU format is used when bits are received from the network medium by the NIC of a host?",
    options: ["File", "Frame", "Packet", "Segment"],
    answer: "Virtual DOM",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question:
      "How many times can you perform leading zero compression in a single IPV6 address?",
    options: [
      "As often as you like",
      "Only once",
      "Twice",
      "You cannot perform this type of compression in an IPV6 address",
    ],
    answer: "user interface framework",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question:
      "A router is connected to switch with a Single link. Which inter-VLAN method is used here ?",
    options: [
      "ROAST",
      "Router With subâ€¢mterfaces",
      "Router with multiple interfaces",
      "Switch Virtual interfaces",
    ],
    answer: "Jordan Walke",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question: "Calculate the valid number of hosts in 192.0.0.22/24",
    options: ["256", "65536", "254", "65534"],
    answer: "254",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "Which class is used for research purposes?",
    options: ["class C", "class A", "class D", "class E"],
    answer: "JavaScript transpiler",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question: "Find the network address for 172.165.56.35/27?",
    options: [
      "172.165.56.32",
      "172.165.56.33",
      "172.165.56.63",
      "173.165.56.32",
    ],
    answer: "172.165.56.32",
  },
  {
    id: 22,

    question:
      "Which of the following statements is true about the ping command?",
    options: [
      "The ping command checks for available printers on the network.",
      "The ping command tests connectivity and measures round-trip time to a specific device using its IP address.",
      "The ping command activates the encryption protocols for secure communication.",
      "The ping command automatically fixes network errors.",
    ],
    answer:
      "The ping command tests connectivity and measures round-trip time to a specific device using its IP address.",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question: "What is a requirement for nonoverlapping Wi-Fi channels?",
    options: [
      "different security settings",
      "discontinuous frequency ranges",
      "unique SSIDs",
      "different transmission speeds",
    ],
    answer: "discontinuous frequency ranges",
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: "Identify the private address range in Class B",
    options: [
      "10.0.0.0 - 10.255.255.255",
      "172.16.0.0 - 172.31.255.255",
      "192.168.0.0 - 192.168.255.255",
      "173.16.0.0 - 172.31.255.255",
    ],
    answer: "172.16.0.0 - 172.31.255.255",
  },
  {
    id: 25,

    question: "Which of the following is NOT a valid IPv4 address format?",
    options: ["192.168.1.1", "10.0.0.4", "172.16.31.12", "255.255.255.256"],
    answer: "255.255.255.256",
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question:
      "From the given options, identify core capabilities of cloud (Select TWO CORRECT options)",
    options: [
      "Rapid Elasticity",
      "Reliability",
      "Security",
      "Resource pooling",
    ],
    answer: "super()",
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question:
      "From the given options, identify core capabilities of cloud (Select TWO CORRECT options) ",
    options: [
      "Rapid Elasticity",
      "Reliability",
      "Security",
      "Resource poolingS",
    ],
    answer: "Javascript XML",
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question: "Name few popular PAAS offerings (Select TWO CORRECT options)",
    options: ["LinkedIn", "Pixlr", "IBM Bluemix", "Google App Engine"],
    answer: "Javascript XML",
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: "Which layer belongs to SAAS cloud service model?",
    options: [
      "Application and Data",
      "Application and Runtime Environment",
      "Storage and Data",
      "Networking and Operating systems",
    ],
    answer: "Application and Data",
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question:
      "Which of the following options does not represent cloud service models?",
    options: ["IAAS", "PAAS", "ISP", "SAAS"],
    answer: "ISP",
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question:
      "A network is configured with VLANs 10, 20, 30, 40 & 50 with at least 1 EUD respectively. Which among the following commands is to be executed to allow traffic of VLANID 10,30 and 50 only in a pc",
    options: [
      "switchport access vlan 10 30 50",
      "switchport mode trunk valn 1-10,30,50",
      "switchport mode trunk allowed VLAN 1-10,30,50",
      "switchport mode access",
    ],
    answer: "switchport mode trunk allowed VLAN 1-10,30,50",
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question:
      "In a network, 2 host devices are configured to VLAN 1O and VLAN 20 respectively. Which among the following statements is wrong in this scenario ?",
    options: [
      "Hosts can communicate between them only if they are configured under the same VLAN ID",
      "Hosts can communicate between them only if they are configured under Default VLAN ID only",
      "Hosts can communicate between them without any changes",
      "Hosts cant communicate between them in this scenario",
    ],
    answer: "Hosts can communicate between them without any changes",
  },
  {
    id: 33,

    question: "Name few popular PAAS offerings (Select TWO CORRECT options)",
    options: ["LinkedIn", "Pixlr", "IBM Bluemix", "Google App Engine"],
    answer: "IBM Bluemix",
    // answer: ["IBM Bluemix", "Google App Engine"],
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question:
      "How does a Cisco Unified Wireless Network respond to Wi-Fi channel ovelap?",
    options: [
      "It allows the administrator to assign the channels on a per-device or per-interface basis.",
      "It segregates devices from different manufactures onto different channels.",
      "It analyzes client load and background noise and dynamically assigns a channel.",
      "It alternates automatically between 2.4 GHz and 5 GHz on adjacent access points.",
    ],
    answer:
      "It analyzes client load and background noise and dynamically assigns a channel.",
  },
  {
    id: 35,

    question:
      "Which function forwards frames to ports that have a matching destination MAC address?",
    options: [
      "frame flooding",
      "frame filtering",
      "frame pushing",
      "frame switching",
    ],
    answer: "frame switching",
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: "which of the following VLAN IDs fall into the Normal Range?",
    options: ["1001", "1003", "1005", "1007"],
    answer: "frame switching",
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question:
      "Which mode should be configured for the ports that are connected to an EUD and a Switch, respectively?",
    options: [
      "Access Mode & Trunk Mode",
      "Trunk Mode & Access Mode",
      "Access Mode & Access Mode",
      "Trunk Mode & Trunk Mode",
    ],
    answer: "frame switching",
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: "In which CLI mode. trunk mode can be configured for a port?",
    options: [
      "User Mode",
      "Privilege Mode",
      "Global configuration mode",
      "specific configuration mode",
    ],
    answer: "frame switching",
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question: "How will a Switch update its MAC-Address Table?",
    options: [
      "Learns from the Destination MAC Address of a Frame with respect to the exit interface",
      "Learns from the Source MAC Address of a Frame with respect to the incoming interface",
      "Learns from the Destination Port Number of a Frame with respect to the exit interface",
      "Learns from the Source Port Number of a Frame with respect to the incoming interface",
    ],
    answer:
      "Learns from the Source MAC Address of a Frame with respect to the incoming interface",
  },
  {
    id: 40,

    question:
      "How does a Cisco Unified Wireless Network respond to Wi-Fi channel overlap?",
    options: [
      "It allows the administrator to assign the channels on a per-device or per-interface basis.",
      "It segregates devices from different manufactures onto different channels.",
      "It analyzes client load and background noise and dynamically assigns a channel.",
      "It alternates automatically between 2.4 GHz and 5 GHz on adjacent access points.",
    ],
    answer:
      "Learns from the Source MAC Address of a Frame with respect to the incoming interface",
  },
  {
    id: 41,

    question:
      "Jimmy, a network admin wants to send multiple VLAN traffic between switches. What modes should he configure the switch ports, to achieve this?",
    options: ["Access", "Trunk", "Both A and B", "None A and B"],
    answer: "Trunk",
  },
  {
    id: 42,

    question:
      "What keyword describes the mechanism of a switch used to get the frame to the correct destination device?",
    options: [
      "Advancing",
      "Flooding to the destination",
      "Forwarding",
      "Dropping",
    ],
    answer: "Forwarding",
  },
  {
    id: 43,

    question:
      "A global Enterprise network wants to use VLAN in their projects. Out of the given options which VLAN they can use?",
    options: ["1003", "1002", "1005", "1008"],
    answer: "1008",
  },
  {
    id: 44,

    question: "What are two functions of a Layer 2 switch? (Choose two.)",
    options: [
      "makes forwarding decisions based on the MAC address of a packet",
      "selects the best route between networks on a WAN",
      "moves packets within a VLAN",
      "moves packets between different VLANs",
    ],
    answer: "makes forwarding decisions based on the MAC address of a packet",
    // answer: [
    //   "makes forwarding decisions based on the MAC address of a packet",
    //   "moves packets within a VLAN",
    // ],
  },
  {
    id: 45,

    question:
      "What will be the course of action of a Switch, If the MAC Address associated with all the connected interfaces is learned and a new switching request for an unknown destination MAC Address comes in?",
    options: [
      "The switch forwards the packet and adds the destination MAC address to its table",
      "The switch sends a copy of a packet to CPU for destination MAC address learning",
      "The switch floods packets to all interfaces except the receiving interface",
      "The switch drops the received frame",
    ],
    answer:
      "The switch sends a copy of a packet to CPU for destination MAC address learning",
  },
];
